STEPHEN GAVIN SEARS

370 Lancaster Ave., Haverford, Pennsylvania 19041 ● 563-340-8754 ● searssgavin@gmail.com ● https://gavin-sears.github.io/sgavinsears/

Profile:

Graduate student in Computer Graphics and game technology at University of Pennsylvania. Dual-enrolled as a Computer Science Major and Visual Studies Minor at Haverford College. Experienced with coding and software design in Python, C#, Java, C++, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Strong writer and communicator with academic experience in computer graphics, machine learning, data science, data structures and algorithms. Work experience with C#, Unity, Blender, Microsoft Office, Microsoft SQL. Strong IT services skills.

Education:

Computer Science Major & Visual Studies Minor - Haverford College, Haverford, PA

Aug. 2021-Present

Relevant Coursework:

Machine Learning, Computer Graphics, Game Design, Analysis of Algorithms, Data Science, Introduction to Data Structures, Discrete Mathematics, Computer Organization, Encoding Music, Multivariable Calculus, Financial Accounting

Work Experience:

Digital Scholarship Project Assistant - Bryn Mawr College, Ardmore, PA (10-14 hrs/week)

Sep. 2023-Dec. 2023

- Tested a project on the Oculus Quest used in a Bryn Mawr College student's thesis.
- Optimized 3D models in Blender by editing shaders, baking textures, and decimating objects.

Incubator Fellow - Haverford College, Haverford, PA (35 hrs/week)

Jun. 2023-Jul. 2023

- Co-founded a game studio, Lemon Dragon, to produce Word Wizard, an English language learning video game, with a team of developers.
- Scripted and designed dynamic UI systems for reading comprehension games using C# in Unity.
- Managed and troubleshot file repositories in Github using command line and GitHub desktop.
- Utilized 3D modeling, texturing, and shading to create ready-to-use game assets
- AGILE scrum

Software Engineer & Systems/Hardware IT Specialist - Sears Mfg. Co., Davenport, IA (40 hrs/week) Jun. 2022-Aug. 2022

- Worked on MVC format web-based applications by utilizing Microsoft SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, PHP, and Azure DevOps
- Troubleshot project issues by correcting payroll information in test software, which reportedly was accurate to the cent when referenced.
- Stood in for IT and Hardware specialists

Systems/Hardware IT Specialist - Sears Mfg. Co., Davenport, IA (40 hrs/week)

Aug. 2020-Aug. 2021

- Reimaged and replaced memory in 150 PCs company wide
- Worked extensively with Windows 7 and Windows 10 Systems
- Managed factory production flow via Manage 2000 MRP Personal Workstation
- Stood in for IT and Hardware specialists

Service and Leadership Experience:

Co-Head of the Bi-Co Computer Graphics Club - Haverford College, Haverford, PA

Sep. 2023-Present

- Managed funding requests and worked with a team to make important club decisions
- Recruited members through classes and personal connections
- Planned to teach workshops on 3D modeling in Blender, Unity, C++ OpenGL, and more. Also planned to assist with other workshops.

Percentage Project - Greater Philadelphia Area, Philadelphia, PA

Sep. 2023-Present

- Distributing and collecting feedback surveys on computer science courses at Haverford College.
- Planning spring social media campaign to boost participation.

Professional Development:

Languages: approximated A2 French Language Skills, Elementary proficiency Indonesian

Programming Languages: Python, Java, C#, C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, swift, MS SQL

Libraries: Pandas, Matplotlib, Networkx, Pygame (Python), Unity Scripting (C#), OpenGL (C++), JQuery, Three.js (Javascript), Scenekit

Software: Unity, Blender, Maya, Microsoft Office, including Excel, SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS), Xcode, Latex, Markdown